<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Nicholas Hugh Sam</title>
  <subtitle>My personal blog.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://nicholashughsam.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://nicholashughsam.com/"/>
  <updated>2024-08-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://nicholashughsam.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Nicholas Hugh Sam</name>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Social media is just a zap of time (#010)</title>
    <link href="https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-21/"/>
    <updated>2024-08-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-21/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not bad at work, honestly. Today, I saw myself staying until my 2 years mark, but I know how quickly things can change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started watching The Departed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proud to have squeezed in a good gym session (realized that there&#39;s still something messed up with my left glute, it was apparent when I did single leg RDLs on the landmine).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supper with Rob and Nhu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, I came back home at 12 and thought I&#39;d be able to sleep earlier today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan was to get home, take my shower quickly, write my daily entry, brush my teeth, talk to my love and go to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I came back home, read 1 chapter of manhwa and then scrolled for 20 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scrolling is such a waste of time, I really rarely remember whatever I scrolled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s like in the movie &amp;quot;Office Space&amp;quot; where Andy asks to be &amp;quot;zapped&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just spend time on social media, look at the time and boom, 20-30 minutes have passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It really is a huge waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I was still able to finish all I had to do today so I don&#39;t feel shitty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But man, I have to start building the habit of breaking myself off of social media.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The truth shall set you free (#009)</title>
    <link href="https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-20/"/>
    <updated>2024-08-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-20/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting back into a work flow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went for a walk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watched Liar Liar (movie).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MBPC practice (my legs felt really good after yesterday&#39;s off-court. Need to remind myself to take smaller steps, but high frequency when I run).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got a nice follow-up message from Lis (congrats on getting into your program and charging more for your services !)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liar Liar was a great reminder of John 8:31-32 &amp;quot;[...] and the truth shall set you free.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember at some point being so drawn to the concept of &amp;quot;Radical Honesty&amp;quot;, which is the practice of not lying at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, I always felt compelled to lie about everything and anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to fit in, trying not to hurt people&#39;s feelings, trying not to get rejected, trying to be funny, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I first heard about it, there was something so raw that just drew me in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I never quite followed through with making radical honesty a practice, but as I&#39;m advancing in my inner work journey, I can see a lot of parallels between radical honesty and the concept of being authentic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At it&#39;s core, RH and authenticity are the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of them are about being and &lt;strong&gt;owning&lt;/strong&gt; who you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&#39;s honestly liberating (no pun intended).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think part of the practice of lying came from business. Our society is so drawn to money and business, being essentially THE field where money rules everything, has influenced our society to take a business approach into our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone knows that 99% of businesses lie especially when they&#39;re selling so it normalized it into our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But imagine a world where we couldn&#39;t lie? There would be &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; of damage done at first, but my intuition tells me that it would make the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who knows, this is truly something we&#39;ll never know.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Overthinking is a coping mechanism (#008)</title>
    <link href="https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-19/"/>
    <updated>2024-08-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-19/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked at JB&#39;s place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had a surprising conversation with her middle sister.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got a decent amount of work done. I think if I concentrate on completing 3 tasks per day, put on some music, I can make it work temporarily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ate lunch with JB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played overcook with JB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Died at the off-court MBPC practice ( felt really good to push myself, but did not feel good to feel like fainting haha)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Late night call and physically dying with JB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overthinking is a coping mechanism we use to not do the action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While thinking about my workshop, I was thinking of all the different reasons why we do not take action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of them is that we spend more time thinking about the problem than taking action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I asked myself &amp;quot;Why do we / I overthink?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the conclusion I&#39;ve reached is that overthinking is less scary and less effort than actually doing the thing and finding out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a pervasive idea that has been reinforced by society. This idea of being smart, being intellectual, thinking through your problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more I advance in my inner work journey, the more I realize that solution to all problems is simply to take more action and try things out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember about 8 years ago or so, I came up with this theory to &amp;quot;live life like a scientist&amp;quot; where the perfect way of living was to pose some hypotheses and try to prove or disprove them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is even more relevant now than it was 8 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With social media, internet and everything, it becomes so much easier to pretend you&#39;re doing something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it be by watching Tik Tok videos, consuming podcasts, watching youtube, scrolling X or your IG feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only real way of knowing something, anything is to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And overthinking is just another excuse we have to not take action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m here spending hours in my head, thinking about every little detail, trying to make the perfect workshop (because of fear as I mentioned before) and, yet, you know what would probably be better than this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Showing up with the bare minimum plan aka the material for the workshop and doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, when it&#39;s over, simply ask for feedback from everyone who attended on what to keep and what to improve on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, implement whatever feedback was given and whatever I think could be improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This action based approach could probably delivery an amazing workshop after 4 sessions, but that&#39;s too much right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want it to be perfect the first try ! So we think and think and think to the point that it&#39;s officially overthinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You never overthink things that do not scare you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me repeat that: You never overthink things that do not scare you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever overthought doing the dishes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about cleaning your place? Do you spend hours about the perfect way to clean your place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or to shower? Or to brush your teeth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hell no ! (hopefully, if not, my condolences)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We simply do it and improve on it over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sounds oversimplified, but I&#39;m truly understanding that it&#39;s the secret to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s not overcomplicate things, just start with the simple version, take action instead of overthinking the complicated version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voila.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>I am still scared, it&#39;s fine (#007)</title>
    <link href="https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-18/"/>
    <updated>2024-08-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-18/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent MBPC practice (starting to hit my shots higher)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JB cooked some good lunch for me (pork brochette + zucchini invention + rice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked a little bit on my workshop (writing the copy for it is harder than I thought, need to remember to take action and iterate instead of wanting perfect from the get-go)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ate supper at my mom&#39;s (good discussion about family)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JB practiced driving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m sleeping over and getting ready for the next day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holyfuuuuuuck am I tired with my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried writing the description of my workshop today and only managed to write about 300 words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had this epic idea of writing a landing page / sales letter text in the description and instead of making this a reality, I simply stared way too long at my screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I was scared, that&#39;s why !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, scratch that, I am still scared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am scared that I&#39;ll publish the event and absolutely no one will attend it. (except for Danny)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That caused me to get writer&#39;s block.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to make sure that people come, I put the pressure on myself to write the perfect freaking description and because I obviously am not the Mozart of writing event descriptions, I couldn&#39;t write shit !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I thought about something, my head would immediately block it off and say &amp;quot;no, that&#39;s not good enough ! People won&#39;t come with just this&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is totally the wrong approach and against how I want to live and what I want to teach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event should be an expression of being my authentic self and my authentic self is having fun while teacher others about the joys and benefits of living a life more aligned with our true selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am confident if I just manage to think, meditate, visualize the state I am in when I operate from my true self, I will write beautifully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It won&#39;t be a sales-y, pitch-y text. Instead, it&#39;ll be more like art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something that can be felt with their soul, not with their head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am grateful today happened. It&#39;s a good reminder of how I want to live and a good reminder to take action and iterate instead of overthinking and trying to make things perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am confident in my path, I just need to be consistent enough to see it through.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>It&#39;s all about being authentic (#006)</title>
    <link href="https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-17/"/>
    <updated>2024-08-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-17/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Woke up supra late (2:30pm)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooked lunch (eating fresh food hits different)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked on my blog a bit (inspiration from https://tinyprojects.dev/blog)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watched a bit of Hitch (I love movies from that era)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huge realization about what I want to teach (authentic self)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ate five guys burger to uplift JB&#39;s spirit !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went on a wonderful walk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished Hitch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My calls with Danny Miranda have truly unlocked my next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internal progress I have made since starting has been exponential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, my new realization is that I want to teach people about being their authentic self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authentic self / true self is present in all areas of our lives. Whether it be career, relationships, family, hobbies, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you peel all the layers that we have put on, your authentic self is below. It only has positive values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more layers you have put on, the harder it is to tap into your authentic self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Layers are mostly barriers that we have put on in order to protect ourselves as we have aged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we are a child, we have no barriers, we are always our authentic self. There&#39;s no baby in the world that exists that doesn&#39;t act like themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The layers are behaviours we learn from our environment that has consciously or unconsciously instilled fear within ourselves and made us think that being our authentic self is not enough. Or that it is even dangerous to be our authentic self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trauma is an example of a thicker layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being fake with friends is an example of a thinner layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is when you think about the authentic self that you realize money is truly just a vehicule, a tool, a means to an end. If you ask 99% of the population, what they would do if they had 100 million, none of them would answer &amp;quot;I&#39;d chase after more money&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your authentic self does not want money. All those who chase money simply want to be their authentic selves again and think money is the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All those who have accumulated a lot of money simply chased their authentic self in business and it happened to make them lots of money.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Creating my blog (#005)</title>
    <link href="https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-16/"/>
    <updated>2024-08-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-16/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked a little bit and managed to get a bit motivated by talking it out with Aaron.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ate lunch with JB, it&#39;s always nice waking up with her !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went for a long walk, they&#39;re the best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gym session after feeling tired and sluggish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coded my blog with eleventy !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s crazy how long I was putting off creating my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And today I finally decided to do it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me 2 hours to complete, I was so sucked into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this is a perfect example of the sayings &amp;quot;the hardest part is always starting&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;starting is already 50% of the job done&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog isn&#39;t perfect yet and that&#39;s totally fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of what I&#39;m trying to achieve more of is taking action and iterating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog is the perfect example of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has the minimal style I&#39;m looking for, but it can use a tiny bit more styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have to make it available to the internet !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now though, it&#39;s 2:30am, I feel like a night owl / degenerate so Ima stop here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feels nice to put in some work and create something out of nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Pure joy is being your authentic self all the time (#004)</title>
    <link href="https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-15/"/>
    <updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-15/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I fell asleep at work today. I literally have no energy for work, it&#39;s super draining.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did have 2 good meetings about the company. One thing I realized is that I love making the company better, I have a vision on what can improve how the company works as a whole and it&#39;s something that fires me up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went for a wonderful walk in the sun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Awesome awesome last call with Danny Miranda, the energy I felt and emitted was off the chart. Definitely worth it as it allowed me to set the standard on how I want to show up in the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I set the date for my workshop to be September 7th.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good Badminton Practice (The key to unlocking the overhead is the initial rotation / pivot. If you concentrate on pivoting quickly, you&#39;ll be more comfortable playing the overhead)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Picked up JB at her practice (Great discussion in the car which validated that she&#39;s an excellent partner and willing to support me in my shenanigans)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The energy I felt getting off my last call with Danny was exceptional. It really set the bar for how I live my days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s crazy to think that every day, I am allowing myself to feel less than 25% of how I felt during the call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;ll be part of my mission to make people feel this type of energy because once you feel it, it&#39;s impossible to go back to the way you were. You become aware that life can be filled with joy, laughs, smiles, abundance, expansion, curiosity and awesomeness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This starts with living a more authentic life. Whenever we choose something that is not aligned with ourselves, we diminish who we truly are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it be scrolling on our phones instead of sleeping, working a job we don&#39;t like, being mean when we don&#39;t want to or even saying &amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; when we wanted to say &amp;quot;no&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time we do this, we are teaching ourselves, our body, our mind that it&#39;s okay not to be ourselves. It&#39;s okay if we feel shitty. If we do this long enough, we eventually think that being shitty is just the default mode of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s like being in prison without physically being there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it doesn&#39;t have to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This starts by recognizing our authentic self in every situation and &lt;strong&gt;taking the right action&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a world where you are 100% aligned with yourself, every day, you wake up and every action you take is aligned with yourself. Holy shit, wouldn&#39;t that feel good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&#39;t have to be fake anymore, you don&#39;t have to push down your feelings or put up a front, you don&#39;t have to do anything you don&#39;t really want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pure joy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Quit, it&#39;s the right thing to do (#003)</title>
    <link href="https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-14/"/>
    <updated>2024-08-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-14/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boring day at work, sales engineer might not be for me because I am unable to be authentic and tell the truth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discovered 2 fire songs: For Cryin&#39; Out Loud! by FINNEAS and Dream by Keshi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went for a walk which made my sore back/hips feel 10000x better; good reminder that walking is &lt;strong&gt;essential&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Officially became an uncle !! Congratulations again to my broski and sistah (in law).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Little impromptu date with JB, we went to Clip n Climb, it was very fun. Scary, but fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discovered SHOP SANTE and loved it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooked salmon, string beans and pasta with rose sauce.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I seriously thought about quitting work today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually know the truth, the truth is that I do want to quit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second truth is that I&#39;m also scared about not having money to pay off my mortgage and having to downgrade my lifestyle significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third truth is that I ultimately know I have to quit for my own well being, values and the person I want to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not make sense to stay at a job which makes me unhappy, unfulfilled and makes me feel like I&#39;m an underachiever for not putting my all into his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is nothing I would love more than to give my all to work I am passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this ain&#39;t it chief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only belief I need is the belief that everything will be alright. If I quit, I will figure out a way to cover my expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not serve me to ponder and ponder and ponder about what I&#39;m going to do and, frankly, I now know myself well enough to know that no matter what backup plan I come up with, I will throw it out of the window less than 3 months in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just need to muster up the courage to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s crazy that my #1 concern is financial (expected), but my #2 concern is what people at my company will think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am literally letting people&#39;s opinions of me, stop me from helping myself and even helping them. The fact they have me as an employee is a disservice to them. Instead of me, they can have someone who is passionate about my role and who would put it 5x more work than me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negative energy is present in the world when people do things they are unhappy about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me at my current job is an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more I stay, the more negative energy I create for myself, the company and the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s time to take a leap of faith before I turn 30 and try to create positivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bias to action and workshop (#002)</title>
    <link href="https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-13/"/>
    <updated>2024-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-13/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tired again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Felt a bit more motivated to work and got a bit of it done, but I&#39;m still in a work rut.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went for a marvellous walk during lunchtime where I thought more about becoming an influencer and what would that entail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Over thought a little bit about what should I do with my life, what do I think is play aka effortless, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rage room with Mr. PDS (it was alright, would not recommend because the environment is too controlled 5/10).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MBPC Practice (good practice, need to improve on my backcourt forehand cross and backcourt overhead straight smash).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listened to Diary of a CEO with Codie Sanchez (big concepts to remember is bias to action and what are you obsessed about)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treated myself to some poulet rougeeee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote an article / blog about having bias to action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slept later than I wished (currently 12:30)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While listening to the Diary of a CEO episode with Codie Sanchez, I realized that the most important thing when consuming content is simply remembering and actioning 1-2 concepts. That is all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s impossible to recall every single piece of advice; however, if there&#39;s 1 that sticks with you, that is the aim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also thought of making doing some sort of newsletter series about this. Where I listen to podcasts or videos and write an essay about 1 big important concept that struck my chord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other thing that caught my brain during the podcast is this concept of obsession. Find what you are obsessed about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed that every time I consume anything, the one thing I always look for is advice / tips on how to live a better life. It&#39;s truly one thing I am absolutely obsessed about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I wrote a whole ass article about having bias to action and it gave me an excellent idea for my workshop / seminar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about a workshop on applying the action-iteration approach on how to find your passion / obsession / what you want to do with your life (gosh that&#39;s such a long sentence).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;ll have all the elements, story-telling, theory behind why I think action-iteration approach is a cheat code of life (especially for smart / overthinking people) and, at the end, the workshop element is to create an IRL Call-To-Action by having people write down 1 thing they&#39;re supposed to action on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about maybe putting every one in a group chat or fb group where they each post what they should do and see if they follow through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last idea I had was possibly making this recurring on a weekly basis, we meet once a week, for 2 hours, and we discuss about if we took action or not, if someone didn&#39;t I can dive deeper into WHY they didn&#39;t take action and people can learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to Alcohol Anonymous.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Reminder of my goals (#001)</title>
    <link href="https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-12/"/>
    <updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://nicholashughsam.com/posts/2024-08-12/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tired&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not motivated to work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wonderful having JB over&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Off-court workout that was cut short + got ice cream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Came home, JB complemented me on my singing of Confirmation by Biebs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bought some ice cream for JB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After coming back from an amazing camping trip, it felt so bad working my job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Camping was pure outdoors, bonding with friends, being active, no screen-time, being in nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My job is 100% indoors, looking at a screen, talking to my coworkers through a screen, no movement, being on the computer all day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t figured out how I want to add value to the world yet, which is what will pay me money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I&#39;m massively certain of the lifestyle I want so that I can be happy and my best self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not a very complicated list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physical activity: I want to be able to workout every single day, be athlete and have a healthy body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Movement: Without counting the workout, I want to achieve 10k steps just by living; without having to consciously do steps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading: I love reading and have not found a way to integrate it fully into my routine yet. I used to love taking public transit for this reason. Consuming knowledge and learning in an offline, focused manner resonates with me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing: Starting with this very first post, writing is my medium of choice to organize my thoughts and to share them also.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proper Nutrition: I am so far off right now because I still rely heavily on my mom&#39;s cooking. I want to reach a state where I can eat healthy 95% of the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surrounded by like-minded people: This is a big big big one. I love Montreal and I think it really has the potential to be a California or an Austin in terms of health, fitness, lifestyle, self-development. I will become someone who attracts that core community I am looking for, I cannot be the only one in the city who wants a different life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aligned work: I tried 4 different corporate jobs and none of them were fulfilling. I even achieved my salary goal 3 years earlier than I thought and that didn&#39;t change much. In order for me to be my best self, I know that I need to work with people. In what capacity, I am not sure yet. I believe there are a lot of unhappy people that do not need to be (myself included) and I&#39;d love to play a part in helping those people. Teacher? Coach? Influencer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day, I need to remember that the above is my goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything else is noise from external pressures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I realized as I typed this out that I can start a few of my ultimate goals TODAY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s get the party started.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>